(忆往昔)
我以为天使是守护者
I thought angels were supposed to be guardians.
毛茸茸的翅膀  戴着光环
Fluffy wings,halos --
不是这么混蛋
You know, not dicks.
去读读《圣经》  天使是上帝的战士
Read the Bible. Angels are warriors of God.
我是个士兵
I'm a soldier.
我认为  我知道路西法最新皮囊是谁了
And I think I know the identity of Lucifer's newest vessel.
这位是杰夫森·鲁尼
I give you one Jefferson Rooney,
美国总统
President of these United States.
我知道你肯定会成为个好父亲
I just know you'd make an amazing father.
一个拿非利人要诞生了
A nephilim is come into being.
天使和凡人的后代
the offspring of an angel and a human.
路西法
Lucifer.
我不能把孩子生下来
I can't have this baby.
我恐怕要坚持
I'm afraid I'll have to insist.
[咒语]
那女孩呢
What about the girl?
凯莉·克莱恩
Kelly Kline.
她是总统助理
She's a presidential aide.
我们不清楚她去了哪  或是是否还活着
We don't know where she went or if she's still alive.
怎么回事
What's happening?
是啊  迪恩
Yeah, Dean.
好啊
'Sup?
比莉
Billie?
那个死神
The reaper?
我不懂
I don't understand.
我们做了个交易
We made a deal.
午夜  要有一个温彻斯特道别
Come midnight, a Winchester goes bye-bye.
我们约定好的
We made a pact,
血盟
bound in blood.
打破誓言
You break that,
会有很严重的后果
there's consequences on a cosmic scale.
小卡  你做了什么
Cass, what have you done?
必须做的
What had to be done.
是啊  你们做了个交易
Yeah, you made a deal.
一个愚蠢的交易  而我违约了
You made a stupid deal, and I broke it.
不客气
You're welcome.
(如今)
我要拔插头了
Unplugging things now.
暗示
Hint, hint.
好  我就打完了
Yes, I'm almost finished.
你不用每晚赢一次那个游戏
You don't have to beat that game every night.
我不同意
I disagree.
好吧  我去倒垃圾
Fine. I'm gonna take this out.
等我回来  我们就关门
Time I get back, we are closed.
你要离开  就这样
You leave. End of story.
你这么大了还玩电子游戏
You're too old for video games.
你在等着玩吗
Were you waitin' to play?
每个人都该玩一把
Everyone deserves a turn.
对不起  我们见过吗
I'm sorry. Have we met?
见过吗
Have we?
闪开
Move out of my way.
否则呢
Or?
否则我会让你闪开
Or I will move you.
是吗  来啊  试试啊
Really? Go ahead. Try.
随你
Suit yourself.
本杰明
Benjamin.
你的天使伎俩对我不好使
Your little angel tricks won't work on me.
你是谁
Who are you?
别  求你
Don't. Please.
[天使语]
没错  叫你的朋友来
That's right. Call your friends.
[天使语]
我等了好久
I've waited so long.
[邪恶力量 第12季第10集]
(凯莉·克莱恩失踪尚无线索)
嗯  我之前也在看来着
Yeah, I was looking at that earlier.
小卡可没闲着  是吧
Cass has been busy, huh?
是啊  没闲着也没找到凯莉·克莱恩
Yeah, busy not finding Kelly Kline
和她的魔鬼圣婴
or her Rosemary's baby.
这样的女人怎么能说消失就消失
I mean, how's a chick like this just drop off the map?
我觉得他就在琢磨那个呢
Well, I think that's what he's trying to figure out.
你有妈妈的消息吗
Hey, you, uh, you hear from Mom yet?
嗯  她昨晚打过
Yeah, she called last night,
说她查到了亚特兰大一个异形者的线索
said she's got a line on a shapeshifter in Atlanta.
我说我们去帮忙  她说"不必"
I said we could come help, and she said, "Don't bother""
显然她"搞得定"
Apparently, she's "Got it""
那她可能就真搞得定
Then she's probably got it.
是啊
Yeah.
妈妈很好
Mom's good.
我觉得她回归日常工作
I just think she jumped back into this
有点急了  不是吗
a little quick, don't you?
我觉得我们的妈妈
I don't think we have the kind of mom
是不会待在家里
who's gonna stay home
给我们做鸡汤的  是吧
and make us chicken soup for dinner, you know?
-你跟小卡谈过了吗  -没有
- You talk to Cass yet? - No.
那你们要继续
So, what, you're just gonna
在厨房跟彼此擦肩而过  不说一句话吗
keep walking past each other in the kitchen, not saying a word?
或许吧
Maybe.
是啊  小卡杀了比莉  但他救了我们
Look, yes, Cass killed Billie, but he saved us.
他救了妈妈  你还要气他多久
He saved Mom. How long are you gonna stay pissed?
我不是气他在乎我们
I'm not pissed that he cares about us, you know.
我很感激
I'm -- I'm grateful.
但比莉说
But Billie said
如果违反交易  会有"严重后果"
there would be "cosmic consequences" if that deal got broken.
你知道那是什么意思吗
You have any idea what that means?
-不知道  -我也不知道
- No. - Neither do I,
但肯定不会是软糖豆和丁字裤
but I'm pretty sure it ain't jellybeans and g-strings.
我的意思是  小卡认为他那样做得对
My point is, Cass thought he was doing the right thing.
我做得就是对的
I was doing the right thing.
-你确定吗  -确定
- You sure about that? - Yes.
我可不那么确定  等出了事
Yeah? Well, I'm not so sure. And when the other shoe drops --
我会再处理
I'll deal with it.
我得走了
I have to go.
有凯莉的线索了吗
Got a lead on Kelly?
不  这是私事
No. This is personal.
什么意思
Meaning what?
另一个天使  一个老朋友  求救了
Another angel. An old friend. He called out for help.
又是可靠的天使电台
Good old reliable angel radio.
他当时在乞求帮助  然后突然停止了
He was begging for help and then he just stopped.
我需要确定他是不是还活着
I need to know if he's still alive.
嗯  好吧  那...
Yeah, all right. Well...
我们一起去
we'll come with you.
你们都去吗
Both of you?
好啊  行  我们帮忙
Sure. Yeah, we could help.
还得确保你不会再做什么蠢事
Gotta make sure you don't do anything else stupid.
好吧  谁想听音乐
All right, who wants music?
不用了
I'm good.
你...
You?
好吧
Okay.
小卡  我们需要了解
Cass, is there anything
关于你朋友的什么具体情况吗
specific we should know about your friend?
好吧  两位  我说
All right. Guys, you know what?
这冷战太傻了
This -- this silent treatment thing, it's silly.
这样不行
It's not gonna work.
不管我们要面对什么情况  我们应该
Whatever we're walking into, we should, you know,
至少有点计划
probably have an actual plan.
你想知道什么
What do you wanna know?
-他开口了  -够了
- Oh, he speaks. - Enough.
小卡  你说你听到本杰明时
Cass, you said when you heard Benjamin,
他在大喊
he -- he was screaming.
那是...
It was, um...
本杰明不会轻易求救
Look, Benjamin wouldn't call for help lightly.
只要他可以  就不会让自己涉险
And he wouldn't put himself in harm's way if he could help it.
这个本杰明听上去蛮酷的
This Benjamin seems like he's pretty cool, you know.
他像是不会做什么冲动鲁莽的选择的人
Like he wouldn't make any half-cocked, knee-jerk choices.
知道我喜欢他哪点吗
Yeah, you know what I like about him?
他再挖苦人
Is that he's sarcastic,
也心思周到  知道感恩
but he's thoughtful and appreciative, too.
-那是什么意思  -好了  看路
- Now what is that supposed to mean? - Okay, okay, the road, road.
哥们  看路啊
Dude, watch the road.
我能行
I got it.
还有什么  小卡
Anything else, Cass?
本杰明一向非常小心
Benjamin is always very careful.
很久以前  他在马德里
Long ago, he found a
找到了一具十分虔诚的皮囊
powerfully devout vessel in Madrid,
她的信念
and her faith, it...
她给了他一切  她的信任和身体
she gave him everything -- her trust and her body.
等等  本杰明是个女的
Wait. So Benjamin's a woman.
本杰明是天使  他的皮囊是女的
Benjamin is an angel. His vessel is a woman.
但不止如此
But it -- it's -- it's more than that.
她不仅是他的皮囊  她...
She's not just his vessel. She's...
她是他的朋友
She's his friend.
嗯
Yeah.
本杰明绝不会让她无谓涉险
Benjamin would never put her in unnecessary danger.
好吧  如果这个本杰明这么小心
Okay, well, if this Benjamin is so careful,
那怎么回事
then what happened?
我不知道  我需要去查个明白
I don't know. That's what I need to find out.
(梅勒芭酒店)
警方报告称是捅伤
The police report is calling it a stabbing.
是啊  官方解释是这样的
Sure, yeah. That's the official story.
我当时在外面
I mean, I was outside, and...
那女人死了  却没有血  拜托
Dead woman? No blood? Come on.
还有这疯狂的焦痕
And these crazy burn marks?
这是邪教  对吧
It's a cult thing, right?
-所以联调局才...  -出去
- That's why the FBI's - Get out.
-什么  -出去
- What? - Get out.
他的意思是  接下来交给我们吧  谢谢
He means we can take it from here. Thanks.
嗯
Yeah.
-等我们好了喊你  -哥们  你没事吧
- We'll call you when we're done. - Dude. You all right?
有事
No.
本杰明和我  曾一起战斗
No, Benjamin and I, we fought together.
他是个...厉害的战士
He was... he was a gifted soldier.
我不知道怎么会这样
I don't know how this could've happened.
有发现
Got something.
看来是天使对天使
Looks like we had a little angel-on-angel action.
这不是本杰明的
This isn't Benjamin's blade.
怎么了
What?
卡西迪奥
Castiel.
我们得走了  快
We have to go. Now.
好吧  我们去见谁
All right, who we meetin'?
他叫伊什姆
His name is Ishim.
我指挥自己的天使营部前
Before I, uh, commanded my own flight of angels, my own battalion,
我和本杰明是他的手下
I served under him with Benjamin.
你觉得他知道是怎么回事
And you think he knows what's going on?
问问便知  你们在这儿等着
We'll find out. You wait here.
-等等  什么  -伊什姆叫我单独去
- Wait. Excuse me? - Ishim said to come alone.
他不喜欢人类
He doesn't like humans.
如果我打算再做什么蠢事  我会告诉你的
If I plan to do anything else stupid, I'll let you know.
米拉贝尔  伊什姆
Mirabel. Ishim.
这么久没换皮囊  不错啊
Kept your vessels all this time. I'm impressed.
我们没那么不小心
We are not careless.
但你  卡西迪奥
But you, Castiel...
我更喜欢以前的你
I liked the old you better.
我们等了好久
We've been waiting.
现在没了翅膀  出行的确是更费时了
I suppose it does take longer to get places now without our wings.
这事跟你也有关  是吧
You had a hand in that, correct?
米拉贝尔
Now, Mirabel,
有些天使还把卡西迪奥当作英雄呢
some angels think of Castiel as a hero.
他离开我们后  还自己指挥了一群人
After he left us, he had his own flight to command.
巴尔萨泽  乌列尔
Balthazar, Uriel.
都是很棒的士兵
Great soldiers.
当然  都死了
Both dead now, of course.
这也跟你有关
You had a hand in that, too.
他是个英雄
So is he a hero?
还是捣乱分子
Is he a spanner in the works?
我也说不清
I don't know.
我不是英雄
I'm not a hero,
但有时做正确的事就得做出牺牲
but sometimes doing the right thing requires sacrifices.
是啊
True,
但似乎总是其他天使
but it just always seems that it's other angels
为了你的好事而牺牲
sacrificing for your good deeds.
他们的翅膀  他们的生命
Their wings, their lives.
你是来羞辱我  还是来谈本杰明的
Are you here to insult me or talk about Benjamin?
不能两者兼顾吗
Can't we do both?
我们失去翅膀后的几年里
In the years since we lost our wings,
我们中还有两人像本杰明那样被杀了
two others from our flight have been murdered, like Benjamin.
只剩我们俩了
We're all that's left.
我怎么不知道
Why didn't I know about this?
我们以为你不会在乎
We didn't think you'd care.
你就要冲进去了
And you're gonna storm in
就...
right...
现在
now.
迪恩
Dean.
感觉有点受冷落了
Feel a little left out over there.
挪过去
Scoot over.
我叫你单独来的
I said to come alone.
他们是我的朋友
These are my friends --
我不怎么听话的朋友
my friends who don't listen very well.
你好吗  我是
How you doing? I'm --
我们知道你们是谁
We know who you are.
去外面看看是不是还有别人
Check outside to see if there are others.
我只带来了萨姆和迪恩
I only brought Sam and Dean.
那是就你所知
As far as you know.
米拉贝尔  是吗
Mirabel, right?
谁想来点派
Well, who wants some pie?
我认识卡西迪奥时  他是个士兵
You know, when I knew Castiel, he was a soldier.
他是个勇士
He was a warrior.
他是天使的天使
He was an angel's angel.
现在看看他沦落到什么程度了
Now look how far he's fallen.
给你糖里加点咖啡吧
How about a little coffee with that sugar?
没有翅膀  回不了家
No wings, no home.
只剩一件烂旧衣服和一对儿没驯化好的猴子
Just a ratty old coat and a pair of poorly trained monkeys.
好吧  你下地狱去吧
Well, you can go to Hell.
迪恩  没事的
Dean, it's fine.
不  不算没事
No. No, it's not.
萨姆  重点不是我  是本杰明
Sam, this isn't about me. It's about Benjamin.
这说对了  真令人耳目一新
Now that is refreshingly accurate.
既然你多带了人来
But since you brought a couple of extra "people"
一起聊天
to our little chitchat,
我们还是去更私密的地方吧
we should go somewhere more private.
我在附近有安全屋
I have a safe house nearby.
我去找米拉贝尔
I'll go get Mirabel.
见到你真高兴  老朋友
So nice to see you, old friend.
去买派吧
Have some pie.
好个朋友啊  小卡
Hell of a friend, Cass.
你为什么容许他那么跟你说话
Why do you let him talk to you like that?
如果伊什姆能帮我找到杀本杰明的人
If Ishim can help me find whoever killed Benjamin,
-那我只能忍着  -好吧  听着
- then I have to. - Okay, yeah, look,
我知道我们需要那个大混蛋
I-I get that we need super dick there,
但是  拜托
but, I mean, come on.
曾与我一同服役的天使在遭人屠戮
The angels that I served with are being killed.
所以我会忍受伊什姆  还有其他的一切
So I will put up with Ishim, I will put up with everything else,
你也一样  我得走了
and so will you. I have to go.
米拉贝尔
Mirabel.
你
You!
你不能灭了我  伊什姆
You can't smite me, Ishim.
我不再无力抵抗了
I'm not powerless anymore.
-怎么会...  -不要
- But how - No!
卡西迪奥  杀了她
Castiel. Kill her!
我认识你
I know you.
我不想伤你们  我不想伤人类
I don't wanna hurt you. I don't want to hurt any human.
让我完成我要做的事
Just let me finish what I started.
别想了  眼罩妹
Yeah, not gonna happen, Patches.
看不到了
Can't see.
萨姆
Sam?
-我看不到  你看到车牌了吗  -嗯
- I can't see. Did you get a plate? - Yeah, I got it.
那是谁
Who the hell was that?!
伊什姆  让我为你治伤吧
Ishim, let me tend to your wound.
我没事
I'm fine.
伊什姆  她怎么还活着
Ishim, how is she still alive?
等等  你认识她
Wait a second. You know her?
-对  -你不必向他们解释
- Yes. - You don't owe them an explanation.
等等
Okay, hang on now.
刚刚那位独眼侠可没想杀我们
One-Eyed Willy back there wasn't trying to kill us.
她要杀的是你
She was after you.
在她闯进来之前  赶紧交待吧
So talk before she kicks in the damn door.
天启之前  天使...
Before the Apocalypse, angels, um...
我们很少来地球
well, we rarely came to Earth.
-是啊  基本从不来  是吧  -对
- Yeah, uh, basically never, right? - Right,
除了这一次
except this once.
很多年前  出现了一次反常状况
Many years ago, there was an anomaly.
反常状况
An anomaly?
他们不会理解的
They won't understand.
小卡  怎么回事
Cass, what's going on?
(缅因州  奥罗诺)
卡西迪奥
Castiel,
我们都到了吗
are we all here?
是的
Yes.
我们来地球干什么  这里好潮
Why are we even on Earth? It's so wet.
别抱怨了
Stop complaining.
我们来  是因为一位天使同僚
We're here because one of our fellow angels
娶了一位人类妻子
has taken a human wife.
他们还生了个女儿
They also have a small daughter.
拿非利人  你确定
A Nephilim? You're sure?
父亲有翅膀  母亲是灵长类
Father has wings. Mother's a primate.
这个孩子
And this child
有人类灵魂和天使能量
has a human soul mixed with angelic grace.
-这...  -很危险
- Now that's - Dangerous.
拿非利人是天堂最古老的法律所禁止的
Nephilim are forbidden by the oldest laws in heaven.
-我们就为个孩子下来  -拿非利人会长大
- We jumped down here for a kid? - Nephilim grow up.
他们的能力会越来越强  到时
They grow into their power and then --
整个世界都要遭殃
Entire worlds die.
所以我们来纠正错误
So we've come to set things right.
阿克贝尔  求你
Akobel, please.
回屋去
Go back inside.
听我的...
Just...
你们不该来
You have no business here.
我吗
Me?
你是被派来观察人类的
You were sent here to observe humanity,
观察学习
to watch and to learn.
可你却搞上了一个肮脏的动物
But instead, taking up with a filthy animal.
你不知羞耻吗
Have you no shame?
你怎么敢教训我知羞
Who are you to lecture me about shame?
人类不是动物
Humans aren't animals.
他们大都善良  真诚
Most of them are good and true and...
任何一个了解他们的人  怎么能不爱上他们
How could anyone know them and not love them?
真感人  但我们不是...
Touching, but we're not --
我知道你为何而来
I know why you're here.
卡西迪奥
Castiel.
阿克贝尔  第六唱诗班的六翼天使
Akobel, Seraphim of the Sixth Choir,
你与人类同床  还生下一个拿非利人
you have lain with a human and you fathered a Nephilim.
什么
What?
继续说
Continue.
你打破了我们最神圣的誓言
You have broken our most sacred oath,
惩罚是
and the penalty is...
死亡
death.
处理掉皮囊
Dispose of his vessel.
下一部分  我自己来
This next part, I'll do alone.
不  不
No! No!
别碰我女儿
Stay away from my daughter!
小卡  你...
Cass, you, um...
我们完成了任务
We completed a mission.
好个任务
Some mission.
那很可怕  但那是必要的  是正确的
It was horrific, but it was necessary. It was right.
你说是就是
Well, you say so.
-那女人呢  -莉莉·桑德
- And the woman? - Lily Sunder.
她是天启文学教授
She was a professor of Apocalyptic Literature.
研究天使  会说流利的天使语
Studied angels, speaks fluent Enochian.
我网开一面  饶了她一命
I took mercy on her by letting her live.
结果现在她来复仇
And now she wants revenge.
那她得有一百岁了吧
I mean, she's gotta be what, 100 years old?
不止
No. More.
但她还不知怎么那么厉害
Yeah, but somehow, she's still kicking ass?
不是"不知怎么"  我知道她做了什么
No. Not somehow. I know what she's up to.
她签订了恶魔协议
She made some kind of demonic pact.
保持青春和力量
Keeps her young, keeps her strong.
不被我们的能力所影响
Keeps her immune from our powers.
好  我和萨姆  我们能找到她
All right, but we'll find her, me and Sam.
-不  迪恩  -小卡
- No, Dean. - Cass,
她才不在乎我们  好吗
she doesn't care about us, okay?
她要的是你们
She's gunning for you guys.
我们或许可以跟她讲理
Yeah, maybe we can reason with her.
从四个死掉的天使来看
Four dead angels indicate
她恐怕不会听理
that perhaps she is not reasonable.
如果她有黑暗的力量
If she has this dark power,
我们得全体上阵才能干掉她
it will take all of us to fight her.
我得治好你的伤
And I need to heal your wound.
等等  小卡
Wait -- wait a second, Cass.
她的家人被杀了
Her family was murdered.
我知道你们只是在执行任务  但是
I mean, I-I know you were just doing a job, but --
你是说那些天使该死吗
Are you saying that those angels deserved to die?
-什么  -你觉得我该死吗
- What? - You think I deserve to die?
不是  他不是那个意思
No, no. That's not what he's saying.
那他是什么意思
What is he saying?
我是说  等我们找到她
I'm saying maybe if we find her,
或许可以跟她解释  你现在不一样了
we can explain to her that you're different now, you know?
萨姆  那没用的  她不会放弃的
Sam, that won't work. She won't quit.
好好想想吧
Think about it. Would you?
卡西迪奥说得对  行不通的
Castiel's right. It won't work.
总得试试
We have to try.
他是对的  我们不是在征求意见
He's right, and we're not askin'.
你就让那些猴子那么跟你说话
The way you let those simians talk to you...
卡西迪奥  你什么时候变那么软了
Castiel, when did you get so gooey?
你知道为什么
You know why
我们不该接近人类吗
we're meant to stay away from them humans?
并不是因为我们对他们有危险
It's not because we're a danger to them.
他们对我们有危险  这就是例子
They're a danger to us. Case in point.
我和萨姆跟迪恩的友谊让我更加强大了
Well, my friendship with Sam and Dean has made me stronger.
你不会真那么想吧
You can't really believe that.
你的伤很深  这要疼了
Your wound is deep. This'll be painful.
确定地址没错吗
You sure about this address?
莉莉的车是租的  我打给了租车行
Well, Lily's car was a rental, so I called the company.
我说联调局想找她问话
I told them she was wanted for questioning by the FBI.
-他们定位了追踪器  -你说"确定"就行了
- They pinged the LoJack - Okay, you could've just said yes.
确定
Yes.
怎么打算的
So what's the plan?
我们敲开她的门  好声好气地问她
Well, we knock on her door and ask her nicely
可不可以别再杀天使了
not to kill anymore angels.
如果她拒绝呢
And if she says no?
船到桥头自然直
Then we burn that bridge when we come to it.
-听我们说一句  -你们怎么找到我的
- Give us a second. - How did you find me?
我们是来谈的  我们不是来打架的
We're here to talk, that's it. We come in peace.
听我们说完
Just hear us out.
我们听说了你家人的事
We heard what happened to your family.
我家人
My family?
小卡是我们的家人  我们不能允许你伤害他
See, Cass is our family, so we can't let you hurt him.
允许我
Let me?
我们不想杀你
We don't wanna kill you.
我也不想杀你
I don't wanna kill you.
那很好  瞧啊  大家达成一致了
Okay, good. Look, there we go. Agreed.
听着  天堂针对拿非利人有严格禁令
Listen, it's not Cass' fault that Heaven has these
这不能怪小卡
crazy rules about Nephilim.
-你女儿  -你以为...
- Your daughter. - You think...
她叫梅
Her name was May,
她是那么美丽
and she was beautiful.
那娃娃好吓人
I find that doll disturbing.
她父亲给她的  她可喜欢了  让她玩吧
Her father gave it to her. She loves it. Let her be.
我本来
I had a life,
有美好的生活
a wonderful life,
直到
until...
他们夺走了我的一切
They took everything from me.
-阿克贝尔  求你  -回屋去
- Akobel, please. - Go back inside.
带上梅  快跑
Take May. Run.
你们不该来
You have no business here.
妈妈
Mommy?
没事的  亲爱的
It's fine, sweetheart.
不会有事的  我保证
Everything is going to be fine, I promise.
来吧  来吧
Come on. Come on.
我一辈子  都梦想着天使
All my life, I dreamed about angels.
研究他们
I studied them.
把他们当作我毕生的心血
I made them my life's work,
直到我终于学会了咒语召来了一个
until finally I learned the spell to summon one --
伊什姆
Ishim.
我第一次见到他时
When I first saw him,
就好像见到了神的面孔
it was like looking into the face of the Divine.
我以为他是完美的
I thought he was perfect.
但他
But he
是个禽兽
is a monster.
伊什姆  你做了什么
Ishim, what have you done?
你做了什么
What have you done?
我把我们的秘密都告诉了你
I shared all of our secrets with you,
为了你的宝贝研究向你传授我们的技艺
taught you all of our ways for your precious studies.
我...
I...
我爱你
I loved you.
你不爱我
You didn't love me.
你是对我着了迷  那不是爱
You were obsessed with me. That isn't love.
我爱过你
I loved you.
可你却为他抛弃了我
You threw me away for him.
不  我就不该让你进入我的生活
No. I never should've let you into my life.
我需要阿克贝尔帮我抵挡你
I needed Akobel to protect me from you.
这可不成功  是吧
Well, that didn't work, did it?
你杀了他
You killed him?
这还用说
Obviously.
你还要杀我吗
And now you're gonna kill me?
不
No.
你伤了我的心  莉莉
You broke my heart, Lily.
我要伤透你的心
Now I'm gonna break yours.
妈妈
Mommy!
你根本无力抵抗
You are powerless to do anything.
不要
No.
你...无力...抵抗
You...are...powerless.
不  不
No. No!
别碰我女儿
Stay away from my daughter!
不
No!
我的女儿
I had my daughter
早在我认识天使之前就出生了
long before I ever laid eyes on an angel.
等等  那...
Wait, so...
我女儿是个人类
My daughter was human.
等等
Just...
你信吗
Are you buying any of this?
还挺信的
Yeah, kinda.
那我们得确定一下
All right, well, we gotta make sure, you know.
伊什姆虽然是个混蛋  但...这样吧
I mean, Ishim's a tool, but -- You know what?
我打给小卡
I'm gonna call Cass.
接啊
Come on, come on, come on.
-他不接电话  -好吧
- Yeah, he's not answering. - Okay.
-你走吧  我留下  -什么
- Just go. I'll stay here. - What?
留下你和她在一起吗  开什么玩笑  她...
And leave you here with her? You kidding me? She --
她对人类不构成威胁
She is no threat whatsoever to humans.
而且她听得到
And she can hear you.
好吧
Okay.
我有一千年没感觉这么好过了
I haven't felt this good in a millennia.
真好啊
Oh, goody.
别抱怨了
Quit your whinin'.
你很快就能恢复力气
You'll regain your strength soon enough.
我的手机呢
Where's my phone?
你该把你的东西收好的  卡西迪奥
You'll have to keep better track of your things, Castiel.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
嗯
Yeah.
我理解想报仇  真的
I-I get wanting revenge. I-I really do.
但
But...
为什么等这么久
why wait so long?
我别无选择
I had no choice.
天使坠落前  他们有翅膀
Before the angels fell, before they lost their wings,
根本没法追踪他们
there would've been no way to hunt them down.
但现在
But now...
耐心是一种才能
Patience is a talent.
人如果有目标  有时间
You'd be amazed what a person can do with
你无法想象
a little bit of purpose
她能做到什么
and an abundance of time.
伊什姆说你做了什么交易
Ishim said you made some kind of pact,
你用了黑魔法
that you're using dark magic.
是吗
Did he?
我这漫长的一辈子
I've studied angels all my...
一直在研究天使
very long life.
我是用他们的魔法打斗  听他们说话
I use their magic to fight, to hear them,
维持生命
to stay alive.
天使魔法
Enochian magic.
这怎么可能
That's...possible?
如果你愿意付"入场费"就行
It is if you're willing to pay the price of admission.
每次我用他们的咒语
Every time I use one of their spells,
我的灵魂都会被烧去一点
a piece of my soul burns away.
等它没了
And once it's gone...
你就再不会感觉到什么了
You won't feel anything anymore.
不会再在意什么了
You won't, uh, care about anything anymore.
你不再是人了
You won't be human anymore.
我以前每晚都会梦到我女儿
I used to dream about my daughter every night.
知道我现在梦到什么吗
Do you know what I dream about now?
什么都没有
Nothing.
你不信任我  我理解
You don't trust me. I understand.
但等你哥哥去对质伊什姆
But when your brother confronts Ishim,
那天使会杀了他的
the angel will kill him.
伊什姆在天堂是个大人物
Ishim's a big man in heaven.
如果真相败露  对他太不利
He's got too much to lose if the truth comes out.
等你哥哥死了
And when your brother's dead,
你就不会再阻拦我了
you won't stand in my way anymore.
你会帮助我
You'll help me.
我可以等这个
And for that, I can wait.
小卡
Cass?
你没事吧
You okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
伊什姆也完全恢复了
And Ishim is fully recovered.
嗯  好吧
Yeah. Okay.
或许你不该那么做
Maybe wish you hadn't had done that just yet.
-等等  为什么  -这个莉莉
- Wait, why? - ‭This Lily chick?
她说她女儿是人类
Says that her daughter was human.
我觉得伊什姆
I think Ishim...
可能耍了你
I think he's playing you.
你回来了
You're back.
有什么消息
So what's new?
是真的吗  伊什姆
Is it... is it true, Ishim?
什么是真的
Is what true?
莉莉·桑德的女儿
Lily Sunder's daughter,
是个人类吗
was she human?
-谁告诉你的  -她
- Who told you that? - She did.
她说你迷恋她
Said you were pretty obsessed.
她撒谎
Well, she's a liar.
她为什么要撒谎
Why would she lie?
她是人类
She's human.
他们就这样
It's kinda what they do.
如果她在撒谎  那她还真厉害
Well, if she's a liar, she's pretty good at it.
而你  则很不擅长
You, on the other hand, kind of suck.
你要信谁
Who are you gonna believe?
你的兄弟  还是这肮脏的猿猴
Your brother, or some filthy ape
总一副高人一等的样子  嘲弄你
who's always talking down to you, always mocking you.
小卡和我或许不是总能达成一致
You know, Cass and I might not agree all the time,
但至少他知道他的真朋友是谁
but at least he knows who his real friends are.
为什么他的话让你这么在意  伊什姆
Why do his words bother you so much, Ishim?
他凭什么质疑我的选择
Who is he to question my choices?
他凭什么质疑你的选择
Who is he to question yours?
看来我的一些选择的确
Well, it seems that some of my choices
该受到质疑
may need to be questioned.
告诉我  那女孩  是人类吗
Now tell me. The girl -- was she human?
你不会喜欢答案的
Oh, you're not gonna like the answer.
我以前还羡慕你  卡西迪奥  你相信吗
I used to envy you, Castiel. You believe that?
你从地狱走出来
You survived Hell.
你是上帝选中的
You were chosen by God.
但现在看看你
But now look at you.
你是那么可悲  可怜的弱小
You're just sad and pathetically weak.
现在
So now...
我要帮你
I'm gonna help you.
我要治愈你的人类弱点
I'm gonna cure you of your human weakness
就像我治好了我的毛病那样
same way I cured my own --
把那弱点割掉
by cutting it out.
别动
Don't move.
动手吧
Do it.
你把我轰走
You blast me away,
也会连带上屋里其他的天使
you'll blast away every angel in the room.
我不会有事
I'll survive.
但卡西迪奥  他受伤了
Castiel, on the other hand, he's hurt.
他或许能活下来
He might live
也或许会成为墙上的血污
or he might just end up a bloody smear on the wall.
赌一把吧
Roll the dice.
嗯  我猜到了
Yeah. That's what I thought.
伊什姆  休想
Ishim! No.
你好  我的爱
Hello, my love.
你不是该看住她别来的吗
I thought you were supposed to keep her out of this.
我改主意了
Yeah, I changed my mind.
好决定
Good call. ‭
好吧  B计划  来
All right, Plan B. Come on.
结束了
It's over.
不
No.
我再也不会无力了
I will never be powerless again.
你不能永远把我顶在这儿
You can't hold me here forever.
你坚持得够久了
You held him for long enough.
好了  那么...
All right, so, uh...
现在怎么办
What now?
他死了
He's dead.
你要收手了
Are you done?
一百多年来  我只有复仇
Revenge is all I've had for over a hundred years.
它是我的一部分
It's what I am.
打错了  你要收手了
Wrong answer. You're done.
迪恩
Dean.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我错了
I was wrong.
虽然我真的不知道
And...while it's true that I didn't know
我们杀了无辜者  但无知不是借口
we were killing an innocent, ignorance is no excuse.
我真的无法想象你深重的丧亲之痛
I truly can't imagine the depths of your loss.
那是你的孩子
This was your child.
我无法想象那痛苦
I can't imagine the pain.
如果你离开这里
So if you leave here
又觉得你不能原谅我
and you find that you can't forgive me...
我会等你
I'll be waiting.
谢谢
Thank you.
你应得的
You earned it.
这对我没什么用
Well, this will do very little for me,
但多谢你的好意
but I-I appreciate the gesture.
伊什姆的话
What Ishim said...
你不软弱  小卡  你知道吧
You're not weak, Cass. You know that, right?
显然  你变了
I mean, obviously, you've changed,
但你变好了
but it's all been for the better, man.
你一直陪我们走过这段
And you have been with us every step of this
漫长疯狂的旅途
long, crazy thrill ride.
不管多么疯狂  你从未退缩过
And no matter how crazy it got, you never backed down.
这是很需要力量的
And that takes real strength.
谢谢
Thank you.
小卡  我不喜欢比莉那事的结果  好吗
Cass, I don't like how the whole Billie thing went down. Okay?
我知道你认为你做得对
I know you think you were doing the right thing.
我不是生气  我是担心
And I'm not mad. I'm worried.
因为"严重后果"这种事
Because things like "cosmic consequences"
经常会最终找上门来
have a habit of biting us in the ass.
我知道
I know they do.
但我不后悔  哪怕我要为此付出性命
But I don't regret what I did, even if it costs me my life.
别那么说
Don't say that, man.
如果你找到凯莉和小路西法  你打算怎么办
So what are you gonna do if you find Kelly and, uh, Lucifer Junior?
那真是个拿非利人
It is a Nephilim, right?
不  没那么简单
Oh, no. It's more than that.
普通拿非利人是所有生灵中
An ordinary Nephilim is one of the most dangerous beings
最危险的
in all of creation.
但大天使  还是魔鬼的后裔
But one that's fathered by an archangel, the Devil himself?
我无法想象它的力量
I...I can't imagine the power.
但小卡  说到底  那也是个母亲和她的孩子
But, Cass, at the end of the day, it's a mom and her kid.
你觉得你能...
I mean, do you -- do you think you'll be able to...
曾经  我不会犹豫
There was a time when I wouldn't have hesitated.
但现在  我不确定
But now, I don't know.
那我们怎么办
What are we gonna do?
喝一杯
Let's drink,
祈祷能找到更好的办法
and hope we can find a better way.